EETU LEPPÄLÄ

Game Designer and Developer with a strong foundation in UI/UX and Service Design, developed over 7 years in highly complex, agile environments. As a skilled generalist, I bring a unique ability to gain insights and facilitate understanding between disciplines of game design, development, narrative and art. My approach blends these varied domains to create novel and holistic gameplay experiences.



EXPERIENCE

Indie Game Developer

Sep 2021 - Ongoing

• Designed and developed various unpublished indie games

Tactical RPG / Roguelike (solo project)

Jan 2023 - Ongoing

- Balanced gameplay elements based on playtesting
- Developed a modular system and tooling for producing content and mechanics fast and reliably
- Designed UI systems to display complex info clearly

Rhythm-based Bullet Hell (6 team members)

Sep 2022 - Dec 2022

- Developed a story and thematized core mechanics
- Designed enemy types, encounters and level design
- Was in charge of art direction and game production, including playtesting and task design

Design Consultant (Nitor)

Mar 2023 - Ongoing

- Worked with companies such as VR, Joblink and Elisa as UI/UX and Service Designer
- Participated in internal sales efforts

Designer (Nightingale Health)

May 2016 - Mar 2023

- Helped launch and maintain 4 complex products, including a mobile application for displaying complex health data, a self-testing service with Yliopiston Apteekki, a wellness clinic service, and an integrated health data visualisation service with Aava Virta
- Led the design of a medically approved self-testing service with a team of six people
- Led service design for a wellness clinic service and co-designed systems and processes with consumers and expert users like metabolomic researchers, nurses, receptionists, laboratory technicians, developers and regulatory and legal specialists
- Designed multitudes of features in the launched products such as consumer-facing health data visualisation tools, purchase funnels and reservation systems and self-testing tutorials and guidance
- Did rigorous usability testing to ensure patient safety, emotional safety and usability

Independent Design Consultant

Feb 2015 - Mar 2018

• Worked with clients such as Costo, Magisso, Vallila

SKILLS

Game Design Skills

System design, scripting, balancing, level design, encounter design, progression systems, boardgame design, UI/UX, player research, playtesting and data analysis, UX and copywriting, illustration, animation, data visualisation, documentation

Game Development Tools

Excel, C#, Unity, Blender, Python, Git, VS Code, Confluence, Jira, Figma, Adobe Creative Cloud, Procreate, Aseprite, JS, JSON, HTML, SASS, Multideck

Other Skills

Market research, pain point interviews, business canvasing, retention design, service walkthroughs, contextual inquiry, testing in the wild, in-depth interviews, co-design, accessibility, agile methods

DETAILS

Contact

+358 44 9846937 eetuleppala@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/eetuleppala eetuleppala.com

Languages

Finnish (native)
English (full proficiency)

Education

Master of Arts, Collaborative Design, Game Design minor (Aalto University, 2021 – 2023) Bachelor of Arts, Design, Fine Arts minor (Aalto

University, 2013 - 2017)